The SBI General Super Health Insurance plan was
launched in 2023. It had a total of
four variants, offering
built-in services like outpatient treatment and maternity care.
However, recently,
in 2024, another new variant has been added to the plan,
called Prime. In today's video, we'll explore the
Prime variant of SBI General Super Health Insurance. We'll
understand the eligibility conditions for purchasing it. We'll discuss the
coverage and benefits offered by the Prime variant. What
optional covers does the company
offer? What are the different add-ons? We'll also learn about the
waiting period for different treatments. We'll also learn about the coverage period and the
time after which these treatments will be covered. We'll also estimate the
annual price for the Prime variant of SBI General Super Health Insurance.
SBI General Health Insurance
plans are quite unique. Let's see
what's new in the Prime variant.
Without further ado, let's quickly begin this video.
First, we'll look at the eligibility conditions for purchasing this plan.  Let
us understand that the first
point is the entry age, that is,
what should be the minimum and maximum entry age at the time of taking the policy. If we
talk about adults, from 18 years of age and there is
no maximum age capping.
Any adult member can take this policy and if we talk about
dependent child, then
from 91 days of age till 30 years, dependent child can be a
part of this
policy with their parents.
Dependent children can stay with their parents in this policy
till 30 years, which
gives freedom to dependent children to stay with their parents for a long time.
If we talk about policy type, then
you can take both individual and family floater policies in this prime variant.
What will be the family size, then
in the family floater plan, four adults can be
included in which self-spouse, parents and parents-in-law can be included
and there is no limit on the number of dependent children,
any number of dependent
children.  This policy can be added. There is
no age limit on how long this policy will be renewed. You can renew this policy for life long.
Now let's talk about the
tenure of the policy, that is, how long can you
buy a policy for at one time. You can also take a
long term policy of 1 year, 2 years and 3 years
together.
What will be the premium of this policy? The premium is age-
banded, that is, your premium will be revised after every 5-year bracket.
However, this 5-year bracket can also be reduced
when the age goes to the higher side,
but it will remain age-banded. It is not that
your prices are revised every year. Now let's talk about the
sum insured, that is, how much
can you buy a policy for? This Prime
variant
is a plan designed according to the lower sum insured, that is, in this
you
can get good coverage according to the options of lower sum insured. So, the
sum insured options are available
from ₹ 1 lakh to ₹ 1 lakh.
Now let's talk about the coverages, that is
What coverage and
benefits will you get during treatment under this plan and
the first point we will take here is room
rent, that is,
which category of room can any policy holder take during treatment
and how much claim will be received for it.
We will also talk about ICU charges, so there is no capping on room rent
and ICU charges of any
percentage or any
amount of any category, both of these will be actuals on the covered age, that is, the
room rent expenses incurred during treatment will be covered.
Now there is no capping on your room rent,
but you
live in shared accommodation on your own will.
During treatment, if you share a room with another patient, that is,
on twin sharing basis or
treatment is taken in general ward, then
in this case the insurance company will
also transfer some benefits to you, but what will be the day of
hospitalization, you can claim ₹5000000
per policy year, ₹5000000 per day
hospitalization
for shared  Accommodation and maximum
cannot exceed Rs. 000 in the entire year.
Pre and post hospitalization, that is, the
expenses incurred before and after the treatment for which we are admitted, and the
expenses incurred after discharge, this
plan will cover 60 days of pre-
hospitalization and 90 days of post-
hospitalization expenses. The
condition is that the treatment claim should be
approved by the company and
those expenses should be related to the same treatment and the same medical condition.
You
can claim these from the insurance company as a reimbursement. Day
care procedures, that is, treatments for which
24-hour hospitalization is not necessary.
These medical procedures are completed in three to four hours
and the patient is discharged.
This plan will also cover such listed day care procedures. Now
comes the turn to discuss home care and domicile treatment, that is,
if we take treatment at home.
Home treatment is covered in both categories
and
it will also be covered under this plan.  But there
is a difference between the two. You take domicile treatment
due to some compulsion, either the patient is
not in a condition to be
taken to the hospital
or the hospital where he is to be treated does
not have beds, then
you can also get treatment at home, but there are
some exclusions for this, treatment can be taken only apart from them,
but it is not so in home care treatment.
In home care treatment,
we take treatment at home on our own will,
this treatment has to be taken from the listed home care services, which are service providers,
and first
approval has to be taken from the insurance company that we are
getting the treatment of this medical condition at home,
then you
can also get coverage for the treatment taken under home care and there is no capping in both these
categories i.e. domicile treatment and home care
treatment, it is
covered up to the sum insured.
How much expense of road ambulance can be claimed, that is,
if road ambulance is used in any medical emergency, then
hospitalization claim can be made for Rs. 3,000
Now comes the turn of air ambulance.
If air ambulance is used in any emergency situation,
then claims of ₹ lakh to ₹
lakh can be made per policy year.
This plan will also cover organ donor expenses, that is,
if a policy holder has to
undergo organ transplant, then the expenses of this
organ transplant procedure will
also be covered and there is no
sub-limit on this. Now
comes the turn to discuss the re-insurance benefit.
You can also call it restoration benefit, that is,
when your basic sum insured, which is the
money of your policy,
your sum insured for treatment, gets exhausted, the
cumulated bonus gets exhausted, then the re-insurance
benefit will work. It will be re-
insured equal to 100% of your sum insured, it will be
restored again and for unlimited times.
And the special thing is that
you will get this for both related and unrelated treatments.
If you want coverage for bariatric surgery, that
is, getting surgery related to obesity done  If you
wish, claims up to ₹5000000 can be made
under this Prime variant, but the
conditions of following medical protocols
or the criteria of BMI index
need to be fulfilled, only
after that its coverage can be availed.
Modern treatments, which are very important to be
covered in your policy today,
all the 12 modern treatments
listed by IRDA are
covered up to the sum insured and there is
no capping on any of those treatments.
Now let's talk about AYUSH, i.e.,
alternative treatments, which are
Ayurveda, Yoga and Naturopathy, Unani,
Siddha, Homeopathy, coverage of these can also be availed,
but this policy will cover only inpatient
treatment, i.e., any treatment for which the
policyholder has to be admitted,
but there
is no capping on it. You get coverage of covered up to the sum insured.
Claim
shield is also a part of the standard policy.
You will get all the
non-medical items listed in the Prime variant.
All the items listed in Annex II's List One in the policy words will be covered in the
standard policy.
You will also get the facility of annual health checkup
under the standard policy when your full year is
completed. After renewal, you
can get annual health checkup done up to ₹2000000 and the
final coverage that comes in the base plan
is Enhanced Sum Insured Bonus, that is, if you do
not make any claim in the policy
within the entire year, when you renew the policy,
you will get half the amount extra at 50% of the sum insured for which you have taken the policy. In
lieu of not making any claim, that is, within 2 years,
your basic sum insured will double and the
maximum can be only this much. But if
any claim comes in the future, then it will keep on
reducing in the same ratio i.e. at 50%.
Now, till here, friends, the basic benefits of the
Prime Plan of SBI General Super Health Insurance, which
you will get in the standard policy without
any add-on  You have learned that, now it is time to
discuss the add-ons i.e. optional covers through
which you
can increase the coverage of your plan and can also modify it.
So the first add-on is
Enhanced Re-Insure Benefit i.e.
Restoration Benefit which you get in the standard plan up to 100% of sum
insured unlimited times.
If you
take this add-on, then you will get re-insure benefit up to limited
times 200% of sum insured i.e.
two times your sum insured.
Suppose
your policy is of ₹ lakh and this amount gets
exhausted, then the re-insurance benefit that you will get
after taking this add-on is ₹ lakh
extra amount, double of your basic sum
insured, but
you will have to take this add-on for that. The next add-on is Enhanced
Cumet Bonus. What is Safeguard Cumet Bonus
which increases our sum shot by 50%.
If any claim comes due to not taking the claim, then it will be levied on the
same  The ratio will also reduce but if
you do not want this then you
can take this option which will not affect your Enhanced Cumulative Bonus till a claim of up to ₹1 lakh comes, it will
not be reduced until
you use that money.
You can also take voluntary co-payment under this plan, that is,
whenever a
claim comes in the future, you should
always pay some percentage of that claim.
You can also choose such an option in return of which you will
get some discount. There are two options of co-payment,
10% and 20%, you can choose any of these.
If you feel the need, then
along with co-payment,
you can also choose the option of annual aggregate deductible,
in which you will have to pay an annual limit of ₹1 lakh, 2 lakh or ₹1 lakh
from your pocket.
You can cover yourself with some other plan,
after that the coverage of this plan will start, otherwise
you will get full coverage under the standard policy from this plan, but the premium
is on the higher side or you can take a  If you
want coverage after the limit from this plan, then you
can choose an amount from Rs 1 lakh, 2 lakh or 3 lakh
for annual aggregate deductible. Next
add-on is domestic help and staff insured.
If you have any domestic help,
a maid, a driver or a cook in your house and
you want to get their coverage in this policy, then
you can take this add-on. What coverage will you
get? 2% of your sum insured for room rate and
4% for ICU.
Apart from this, you can also give them coverage for pre and post
hospitalization ambulance charges,
but
you will have to take this add-on.
But there is an entry age condition in this. The entry
age of any staff member you want to add should be between 18 to 65 years, that is, there is an
age
capping here. If their age is more than 65 years,
then you cannot give them this cover.
Next add-on is additional basic sum
insured, that is, your sum insured is
twice the amount for which you have taken the policy.
You can avail extra sum insured
only for accidental treatments, i.e., for
normal treatment, your basic sum
insured will remain the same, but in case of any
accidental injury,
you will get two times extra sum insured of your sum insured if you have
added this add-on in your Prime variant. The
final add-on is the
Wellness Benefit. There are a
total of four features in this that you can avail. The
first benefit is Health Assistant, in which
you can avail AI assisted fitness coaching, i.e., with the
help of Artificial Intelligence, you will be
given some fitness coaching tips,
you can avail of it. Along with this,
you can also avail e-consultation of dietician and nutritionist and there is no limit on the number of consultations. The
next benefit in this
is the Walk Healthy Benefit, which is your
daily step count. If you
maintain it at a good level, then you
can get a renewal discount of up to 30 per step. The
final benefit of the Wellness Benefit is
Unlimited gym membership
means you can earn gym membership on a quarterly basis. It
is necessary to remain active in the first quarter if you want to
keep your gym membership active in the next quarter.
But you will have to take this add-on,
Wellness Benefit, only then you
can avail these four benefits. Now friends,
you have understood all the add-ons till here. Before I
tell you what is the difference between the other four
variants and this Prime
variant, that is,
what things are not there in the Prime variant
or what things are missing, once
we understand the waiting period,
which treatment will be covered after how much time. The
first waiting period is the initial
waiting period of 30 days from the start, that is, for the
next 30 days after we buy the policy,
we will not get any coverage other than accidental treatment. The second
waiting period is for specific diseases.
These are the listed medical procedures and
medical conditions which the company will cover after 24 months, that is, for the
first 24
months, for 2 years.  You will not get coverage for these until then.
Now finally comes the
waiting period for pre-exit diseases. That is, any
medical condition that we declare at the time of taking the policy,
which we already have and which the
insurance company accepts and issues us
this policy, will be called our pre-
existing disease. Its waiting
period is also 2 years, which means
we can cover it after 2 years of taking the policy.
And the final waiting period comes for BP
i.e. hypertension, diabetes and cardiac
conditions, that is, if there is any medical condition related to heart, i.e.
BP related
or diabetes i.e. sugar related, then
you will get coverage for it after 90 days of taking the policy. During this time, if any
claim related to these comes, then the policy will
not be entertained. Now friends, I am going to
tell you the differences
in all the five variants, that is,
what things are missing in the Prime variant, which
you will get in the other four variants because the
Prime variant is placed at the bottom of these five stacks,
which means it has
become the initial variant and the most important one.  The
benefit that
is missing in this plan in this variant is the health
multiplier. Health multiplier means that there are
37 critical illnesses listed in the policy wording.
On diagnosis of these critical illnesses, you will get an additional
sum insured up to two to three times your sum insured.
But this
health multiplier benefit is
not available in the prime variant. You will get it in the
top three variants. The
next coverage that comes is related to maternity, that is,
childbirth
expenses, newborn baby expenses,
or vaccination
expenses.
You get coverage in the top three or top two variants.
But the base variant, which has just been launched, the
prime variant, does
not have the maternity facility. If we talk about global
coverage, that is, if a medical condition is
diagnosed in India and you
want to get treatment outside India, then
this coverage will also not be available in the prime variant
because this is the base variant. In the top two
variants, which are platinum and
platinum infit, both of these
This facility is available within the variants only and the final
difference comes in the coverage of OPD i.e. the
expenses of the outpatient department i.e.
normal visit to the doctor, doctor's
consultation charges are medicines, these are the
top two variants of this plan. Platinum
and Platinum
Infinity Prime because it is the base plan, it does
not have OPD facility. So
after understanding the major differences from the other variants, now comes the turn to know the pricing of this plan
i.e. Prime variant which is a
base variant has been made because the
sum insured in it is also less, there is
no health multiplier benefit, there are
no maternity features, OPD coverage has also been
removed, so this means an
attempt has been made to reduce its premium, that is,
for those policy holders who do not need these features, at least the price should be
kept cheap. For this, let's
check the price once. The family size that we have
taken is of two adults and two children. The
age of the adults is 38 and 35 years and the
age of the dependent children is 12 years and 9 years.
12 years  They have a son and a 9-year-old
daughter. The sum insured is ₹1 lakh,
for which we will check the price. Their address is
New Delhi. There is no pre-aging disease
in this family and no add-ons are
included in the pricing of this policy.
If they want coverage of ₹10 lakh, then this
family will have to pay ₹28,000 to get the Prime variant for one year.
This is the online price. It is
possible that an online discount of ₹5 lakh may
also be included in it. Now after knowing the price of the Prime variant,
this video will be concluded. The health
insurance company has tried to make
this plan even more flexible through the Prime variant
because there were
some features in the other four variants
which the policyholders may
not need. For this, the Prime variant was
introduced and the sum insured was kept low in it.
Apart from this, the more basic things
like no capping on room rent,
no capping on modern treatments,
consumable items will also be covered under the standard policy. There is
unlimited restoration benefit, the rest of the
standard  Benefits: The rest of the standard
benefits have not been reduced, that is,
they have been kept in this plan,
but the additional benefits like
maternity, OPD coverage,
global coverage, critical illness
coverage, those extra benefits have been
removed so that if a policy
holder wants a cheaper policy with
no capping, he
can take this plan. Two more special things that I noticed are that there is
no capping on the entry age of adults, although now this will be the case in most plans,
but the dependent child
staying in this policy for 30 years is also
very positive and along with that there is no
limit on dependent children, whether
two children, three children, four children
can stay in the policy for 30 years, so this is also
quite unique. How did you like the plan, what
good things did you find, what shortcomings did you find? You
can also tell me by commenting. If you liked the video, you
can like the video,
share it wherever needed, and if you
want to subscribe to the channel, you can do that too,
now as you know.  Insurance
Impact channel is currently running a report card
series in which we are reviewing every health
insurance company one by one.
If you want to know more about these insurance companies,
you can watch all the videos one by one by clicking here.
I, Harvinder Singh, now take your
permission. I will take your permission in the next video. Till then,
take care of yourself, stay happy
and stay healthy. Jai Hind.